自动字幕整理+翻译：SuperBart 原作者Techmoan发布于2021年3月27日
On the 6th of March 2021, which is 10 days ago, at the time I'm recording this,
2021年3月6日，按今天录制时间来说，是十天前
a gentleman called Lou Ottens passed away at the age of 94.
Lou Ottens老先生以94岁的高寿过世
And if you're a person who watches this channel,
如果大家经常看这个频道的话，你对这件事应该会更加了解
it's more than likely you're already familiar with this fact because
he is the chat credited as being the inventor of the Philips' Compact Cassette.
因为他被大家认为是飞利浦盒式磁带的发明者
SuperBart：本视频中，磁带可以有不同的意思，请注意甄别:-P
有人说可以用卡带来避免误会，那就用吧(虽然我从来是没听说过)
"发明家"
I want to start off by talking about this word "inventor"
我想用"发明者"这个词引入这个话题
because to me, it conjures up certain images I'm thinking a long time ago.
因为对我而言，这件事能让我脑子蹦出一堆之前就在想的事情
You know, like people working away in a lab and look what I've invented, I think.
比如说，人们在实验室里工作，欣赏着我的发明啥的吧
The Philips' Compact Cassette was invented what I would consider
我觉得飞利浦盒式磁带算是在现代发明出来的吧
kind of in the modern age, you know late fifties, sixties, that kind of thing.
也就是上世纪50年代末，60年代之类的吧
And things weren't really just one guy at that point.
而这件事也不完全是他一个人搞
I mean, I'm sure something came out there was just one blow.
当然，肯定有一下子就能做出来的东西
But the Philips' Compact Cassette certainly wasn't one of those.
但磁带肯定不是这类
It's a little bit like saying, that Steve Jobs invented the iPhone.
有点像是，Steve Jobs发明了iPhone
I mean, you wouldn't say that, would you?
当然，你兴许不会这么说吧
And if you search who invented the iPhone, you're not gonna get one name.
你要去搜索谁发明iPhone的话，你肯定看到的不是一个人
You're gonna get, like there's a team that worked on this product for many years.
你应该看到的是一个团队，经过多年的努力来开发的
It was kind of, half this idea, half that idea, they put those two things together.
有点像是多个想法的群英荟萃
Then changed it and this that on the other era.
然后这改改，那改改啥的
Same thing with the Compact Cassette.
磁带也是这样
So Lou Ottens is credited as being the inventor of the compact cassette.
回到主题，Lou Ottens被认为是盒式磁带的发明者
But I don't think he was particularly happy with that acknowledgement himself.
但我觉得他对这个看法不是很高兴
There's a documentary which came out a few years ago.
几年前有一个纪录片
But he's kind of credited as that in this,
他在那个纪录片也被如此尊称
and you can see he's not comfortable with it.
你也可以看到，他有点不自在
Instead, with his old team.
实际上，(他说)他是和他的团队一起发明的
He said: "Well, it's not really me.
他说：好吧，实际上也不完全是我
I mean, it's a team thing there, were like 40 people working on it at that time."
而是一个团队，那时有40个人在研发吧
He's got the designer there, the guy that drew out the cassette.
拿出卡带的这位是设计师
You know, the engineers, all that kind of stuff.
还有工程师啥的
But the fact is not to take anything away without Lou Ottens
但事实也不是，如果没有Lou Ottens在工作时候想出这个主意
coming up with the idea and saying: "Look, this is what we need to work on!"
然后在那说"兄弟们，我们应该在这方面开展工作"的话
Philips won't have worked on it.
飞利浦公司就不搞这个玩意了
But as far as like "the inventor of it",
但就像其他的"发明者"一样
you know, he's kind of the instigator of the project
他是在飞利浦里，磁带项目的发起者吧
to develop the cassette within Philips.
But again, even outside Philips, there were loads of other people working on this idea.
但又说回来，就算在飞利浦之外，依然有很多人在实现这个想法
And in fact, there were other pre-existing products
实际上，在飞利浦的盒式磁带研发之前
that, you know, predated the Philips' Compact Cassette
市面上已经有很多的类似产品了
and very much along similar lines.
基本思路还都差不多
This is not an idea that just came out of the blue.
毕竟这个想法也不是从石头缝里蹦出来的
The idea of having tape inside a cassette or a cartridge
这种将其放在盒子，或者卡带的想法
that you didn't have to spool onto a machine.
是为了在使用磁带时，不用将其手动缠在机器上
And the way that they went about that was
而他们研发的时候，也融合了一些先前产品的元素
really combining a few things that had gone before.
And those things really set out all the groundwork for the Compact Cassette.
而那些东西也算是奠定了飞利浦盒式磁带中的一些基本元素
This did it successfully, but the people
这个东西确实成功了，但那些第一批尝试这个想法的人呢
that went there first really made this possible.
他们真正证实了这个想法是能实现的
So let's look at some of the products that existed before the Compact Cassette.
现在呢，我们来看看在飞利浦盒式磁带出现之前，有怎样的东西吧
飞利浦盒式磁带之前研发的盒式磁带
In order to understand what pre-existing technologies there were
为了能更好理解先前产品对盒式卡带设计的影响
that could have influenced the design of the Compact Cassette,
we first of need to know when the compact was being developed.
我们得先知道飞利浦盒式卡带是在什么时候研发的
It was first shown to the public at the end of August 1963.
飞利浦盒式卡带本身是在1963年8月底向公众发布的
which, of course means, that the development precedes that.
也就是说，开发是在其之前的事情了
And as far as various things I've read ago,
据我读过的资料，开发应该是从1960-1961年开始的
he either started as a project in 1960 or 1961.
But if we just assume 1960 is when it started,
这里我们假设是从1960年开始的
that's when Lou Ottens walks into his team at Philips
那时Ottens先生跟他在飞利浦的同事们说
and says: "You know what, here's what we need to work on.
我觉得我们应该在这个方向工作
"Um, fed up tried to spool tape onto a real to real machine.
既然大家不乐意将磁带缠在开盘机上
"Let's come up with something simpler,
我们来点简单的，将磁带放在一合适的卡带里，以简便使用
"and in a nice cartridge that's a lot easier to use."
Now of course, Philips had a history of reel-to-reel machines.
当然，飞利浦在开盘机生产方面，有很厚的历史积淀
I mean, this is a slightly lighter tape again, of course.
毕竟，盒式磁带比起开盘机，就是小了一些
But you know, they had a lot of reel-to-reel tape recorders on the market.
但是呢，他们当时有很多的开盘机在售
And in fact, there are a couple of products from their own range
实际上，他们自己研发出来的两台类似机器
that really had a lot of influence on the Compact Cassette.
确实对飞利浦盒式卡带的影响很大
One was this. Now this is branded as a Stellaphone from Stella.
一个是这个，上面的商标是由Stella生产的Stellaphone
But it was made by Philips.
但这个是由飞利浦生产的
This uses three inch reels of tape, and this first came out in 1961.
该机器使用3英寸的开盘带录制，首发于1961
In a slightly earlier version than this one here.
这里有个更早发行的版本
But this older truckload of them,
但是老版发行更多，促使他们继续开发盒式卡带
which encourages them to continue working on the Compact Cassette.
They probably got some more funding for it.
估计是从中搞到更多经费吧
Based on this thing being a big success.
本身这个东西就很成功
Now that uses um three inch reels. I've got one here somewhere.
这台机器是使用三英寸开盘带的，我这有一些
And there's a little three inch wheel
这个是单独缠在一起的，而不是从机器上拿下来的
rather than take it off the machine, it's spooled on there.
So yeah, there's plenty of little machines
显然，当时已经有很多机器使用三英寸开盘带了
out already that use three inch reels of tape.
And one of Philips own product use one of those in a cassette already,
还有一个飞利浦自家产品，采用了装在盒子里的磁带
and this was prior to that in 1957 or 58, this came out.
这个产品可以往前推到1957年末到1958年初
out it's probably the end of 57, early 58.
This thing weighs a ton, metal this thing.
这玩意还挺沉的，全金属机身
Now what's the model number on this? I've just got to remember.
我得想一下这个机器的序列号
Yeah, EL3581.
看到了，EL3581
So this is a Philips dictation device.
这是一个飞利浦牌的听写机
And it just looks like another reel-to-reel machine.
看上去和其他的开盘机没啥区别
But it uses these things.
但是，这台机器用的是这个东西
These are three inch reels again, in a cassette.
装在盒子里的三英寸开盘带
But you'd buy them like this.
你买回来就是这样装好的
You wouldn't have to put your own in here,
你不用再往里面放一个了
although you can open them up to put them on another machine.
虽然你也能打开盒子，将里面的磁带拿出来，放在其他机器上用
So this is Philips' first cassette, I suppose.
我觉得，这也许是飞利浦生产的第一种“盒式卡带”吧
Very rudimentary crew, just two reels
十分原始，就塑料盒里开俩洞
with a hole in these plastic things of the tape going between them.
里面放俩卷筒，上面再缠上磁带
But they're just designed to make, you know, easy snap load, they'd call it.
不过他们说，这么设计是为了“方便快速放置磁带”
So you were just pop it on there.
你就将其放在这里
So that's a Philips cassette from 1957.
这就是1957年飞利浦生产的"盒式卡带"
So that's one thing that predates the Compact Cassette.
在飞利浦盒式卡带出现前，出品的一款产品
But there were some other products that had more of a direct influence on it.
然而有一些其他的产品，对磁带有更加直接的影响
Let me grab a couple of those.
这里我拿出几个举例
两种盒式卡带的融合
Okay, now this is more like it, this is a cassette.
好的，这个更像，基本就是"盒式卡带"了
Since... Well, it isn't a cassette.
毕竟......好吧，这不是飞利浦的那个:-P
This is a RCA sound tape cartridge.
这个是RCA录音卡带，里面是磁带
There's a promo video for this one.
这里有一个宣传片
I suppose it's a film back in the day
应该是当时拍摄的吧
and of course, it's on YouTube, there was a video though.
当然，这个视频在油管上有
And that's from 1958.
是1958年录的
And therefore, a lot of the things that you read
进而，你读到很多的关于RCA录音卡带的资料，都说是1958年出的
about the RCA sound tape cartridge, you'll say:
"Oh! It came out in 1958."
No. That promo video, like a lot of things, preceded the launch of the product.
然而不是这样，像很多东西一样，这个宣传片是在产品出品前录的
SuperBart举例：我校联通宽带(西电联通手机信号很差) David大叔的Amiga视频
And by quite a bit. I mean, RCA had been working on this for ages,
而且是很久之前，虽然RCA研发这个产品很久了
but as you'll be aware from watching various videos
但正如你在很多关于RCA研发过程的视频中看到的
about RCA's development of products, they seem to have a failure to launch.
他们看样子并没有成功发布这款产品
For some reason, the long development into things,
不知为何，开发周期很长，但他们不能很好地将其推向市场
they just can't get it out to market properly.
and they kind of trip up at that last hurdle.
貌似最后阶段，他们翻车了
And that was the case with this as well.
这个也是这样
After years of development, it didn't come out until late 1959.
开发了那么多年，直到1959年才发布
Quite a soft launch, as well.
可以说是软发布了:-P
注：软发布是指在有限或不做推广的情况下新产品上线
I mean, RCA themselves only had two machines I think, when this thing came out.
估计这玩意出品的时候，RCA只有两个机器
But it encouraged some other people, Bell or Bell console, to get on board with it.
然而他们还是吸引了其他人，比如贝尔公司，和他们在这方面合作
And they like went a bit more all in on it,
我觉得和他们合作的公司还不少
so you'll find more machines from other people.
所以，你会看到其他公司出品的机器
(And) RCA didn't really back their own product in the end.
我觉得RCA并没有一直支持这款产品
They kind of sold it. So it's like a time share or something.
他们将其出售了，有点像是出售股份啥的
They sell it off to other people who are buying into it.
他们将这个产品的产权卖给那些投资的人
And then RCA account "Well, we're not too sure ourselves."
然后RCA就说：“我们对这个产品没啥信心”
So yeah, they really fumbled this.
好吧，真就摸着石头过河呗:-P
But what this product is? Perhaps I should have started with that.
但这到底是个嘛玩意？兴许我应该从这里开始讲
It's quarter inch tape.
磁带宽四分之一英寸
Again, much the same as that Philips thing.
和飞利浦用的磁带规格一样
And this was stereo, and the machines had auto reverse on some of them.
这是双声道，有些机器能自动翻带
And it basically, really nice format, sounds alright as well.
而且音质很不错，挺好的介质
I did a demo of one of these, it sounded great.
我录过一些示例视频，音质很好
So this is a kind of 1959 product, so definitely out at the time.
这个是1959出品的产品，在当时绝对很出色
Philips is sitting there thinking: "Let's come out with a cassette!"
飞利浦坐在那里就想：“我们也搞个这样的磁带”
Here's a cassette, but this was a a failure in the market.
这可以说是磁带了，可惜市场上不成功
Partially due to the kind of lack of,
我觉得，一部分可以归咎于RCA对自己家产品缺乏热情吧
uh, enthusiasm from RCA for their own product, I think.
And partially because of the price, in fact, let's go into the price.
另外一方面，就是价格问题了，我们现在看看价格
And let's find that, I've got it on somewhere.
我们来看看，之前我收集过了
Cost $300 for one of the RCA machines, that was $2700 today, with inflation.
当年卖300美元，考虑通货膨胀的话，放现在得是2700美元
You can understand that not becoming a mass market product.
这价格，绝对不可能是大众化产品啊，价格太贵了
It was very expensive.
A couple of nice innovations in this,
这个产品有很多技术革新
you know, four track tape, this is the first time.
比如说，头一回在磁带上有四个音轨
Anyone did four track was for this format
之后很多人都做四轨磁带，家用开盘机上也普及了
and four track became a familiar thing in home reel-to-reel machines.
And also, they slowed the tape speed down to 3.75 inches per second.
而且，他们还将带速降到了每秒3.75英寸
Most tape recorders at the time were running at 7.5 inches per second.
而在当时，很多磁带录音机的带速是每秒7.5英寸
*对于音乐磁带来说
People were wondering: "Well, will 3.75 and
人们就想：好家伙，这磁带带速3.75，上面有四轨道，音质行吗？
four track be good enough for sound quality?"
And they proved it was with this and, uh,
他们后来证实，音质确实行
part of that was down to the input from 3M
一部分原因在于3M为了配套该项目，开发了一种更好类型的磁带
in developing better formulations of tape for this.
Of course, the earlier tapes were quite rough
没错，早期磁带十分粗糙，要想用的话
and for ready, you need to run them at a fast speed and
你走带的速度得快，兴许只能放两个轨道
maybe only put two tracks on them.
So, to get four tracks and at half the speed
所以，为保证在四轨，带速将至一半的前提下
and still sounding good not too much hiss,
音质依然能够很好，没有嘶嘶声
you're developing a formulation, just that kind of pushed that side of the market on.
你得为这方面的市场，搞出一种新的磁带配方
3M were working on the tape for this for years.
3M公司当时开发磁带已有多年
They were aware of this product going to come out at any minute.
他们对该产品随时推向市场十分关注
Now see, we'll have this product, it's going to be massive success in the market.
毕竟已经有了这个产品，将来推出后肯定是热门产品
So 3M gearing up for this product, and RCA are dragging the heels.
所以3M对这个产品意气蓬发，不过RCA意兴阑珊
So, 3M were getting fed up with RCA at this point,
这时，3M算是受够了RCA的不作为
and so, you know, what we're going to launch our own cassette format
他们就想发行自己的盒式磁带，但是还不能叫盒式磁带
our own tape format, shouldn't call it cassette.
Let's call them cartridge at the time, serve them as a cartridge.
我们就把这玩意叫做卡带吧，按卡带看待吧
So they're going to launch their own cartridge system
他们这就推出了他们自己研发的盒式磁带
because they got fed up with RCA, just fumbling and dragging the heels.
因为他们受够RCA做事情太笨，而且兴致不高
And um, this is it, this is the 3M system.
然后，就是这个了，3M的盒式磁带
This, they were showing off in 1959.
他们在1959年展示过这个东西
and then it was 1960 and then 61,
然后是60-61年，最终在1962年12月发布
eventually it came out in December 62.
So I think they proved to themselves that
我觉得他们也证实了一点
it might not be as easy launching a format as they thought
在对RCA动火前，应该意识到推出一个新格式不是一件简单的事情
when they were getting angry with RCA.
So yeah, the 3M revere cartridge system, what is this?
好吧，这个3M Revere 卡带又是个啥玩意？
Well, this is what made the cassette possible.
这个使盒式磁带的诞生成为可能
The headline stats for these are identical to one another.
这两个上面的缺口基本相同
They both are at the same speed, 1.875 inches per second.
带速一样，都是1.875英寸每秒
The tape is an eighth of an inch across.
磁带宽八分之一英寸
The difference was that when the Philips' was launched, it was a mono format.
而区别呢，当飞利浦的磁带发布的时候，是单声道的
To track one going in either direction, you play that side you play that side.
为了播放两面的音轨，你半途得换面
It's just one track.
一面只有一个音轨
Then again, similar idea, two-track system.
这个呢，磁带上也是两个音轨
But they use this tracks for stereo, so you've got a bigger reel here.
但这个是双声道，所以这个开盘带更大
Of course than you would have in a cassette.
当然，飞利浦的盒式磁带上将来也会有
And what happened with this format is the tape gets pulled out of the cartridge.
而这个呢，磁带会从卡带里扽出来
So this is basically spool one.
基本上，里面的磁带就是一卷
And it's spooled up inside the machine, and the tape gets pulled across.
然后磁带被卷进机器里，磁带顺势经过磁头
So you're using your two tracks for your stereo.
这样，磁带上的两轨正好可以弄成立体声
So these were the music format, from the word go stereo music format.
这就是一种音乐介质了，他们的意思是，立体声音乐介质
But the thing that happened with these (is)
但这个东西能让盒式磁带的出现成为可能(的原因是)
the one thing that made the cassette possible
was the proving that you could run a tape at that speed,
他能够证明，磁带可以在那样的速度下运行
and the quality was good enough.
而且质量(音质)也足够好
And that was because 3M being the tape.
这些都是3M能够做出这样的磁带
The people who created this format again, worked on the formulations
那些开发出这类介质的人们，也在开发一种新的降噪系统
to develop a new low noise type of formulation,
which was suitable for music at 1.875 inches per second.
以适配存于带速为每秒1.875英寸磁带上的音乐
So this is really the ancestor of the cassette,
这可以说是飞利浦盒式磁带的原型了
with a bit of this as well, because that's kind of the design.
这个也算一个，左边那个是外观
That's the tape.
右面的是里面的磁带
And you add those two things together, and you end up with that.
这俩一结合，就成这个了
Well, almost. And um, besides that
基本算吧:-P 实际上，抛开那两个，当时市场上还有其他格式
there was another format that was on the market as well.
I haven't got that one here, so I'm going to
我这里没有实机，我这里就给大家
bring up some photos from the Museum of Obsolete Media.
展示一些从Museum of Obsolete Media收集来的图片
Yeah, so you're looking at the Minifon Attaché.
你现在看到的是 Minifon Attaché
This was first shown off in 1959,
在1959年首次展示
but launched in 1960 by the German company Protona, based in Hamburg.
但是在1960由德国汉堡公司Protona发布
They primarily made kind of spy recorder, type devices or miniature recorders.
他们主要生产间谍录音机，打字机或是微型录音机
I've got one of their wire recorders.
我搞来了他们生产的有线录音机
The tape using here is a quarter inch inside this cassette,
这里，他们使用的是6.25毫米(0.25英寸)的磁带
but it's definitely a cassette or cartridge system
但这绝对是和飞利浦的盒式磁带长得很相似啊
that looks similar to the Philips Compact Cassette.
And yeah, it came out in 1960, the time when
这个发布于1960年，正好是飞利浦开始研发盒式磁带的时间
Philips started work on their compact cassette .
Now I'm quite sure that Philips were aware of the existence of the Minifon Attaché.
我敢肯定，飞利浦一定知道Minifon Attaché的存在
After all, they weren't developing the cassette in a bubble.
毕竟他们开发的时候，不是与世隔绝的
They were looking at what was out there on the market already,
他们一定寻找过已在市场上存在过的产品，然后在其基础上改进
and then working on improving upon it.
It's mentioned that they did specifically look at the RCA Cartridge System,
有人说，他们特意注意了RCA的卡带以及3M的卡带
and indeed, the 3M Revere Wollensak System as well.
So I'm quite sure that the Minifon Attaché was also in that list.
我敢确定，他们也在注意 Minifon Attaché
But these are perhaps a little bit more famous.
但这个估计更加著名一些
This one, I'm sure not too many people here have heard of it.
而这个呢，应该没几个人听说过吧:-P
It's not well known nowadays, but that's because it wasn't a success in the market.
现在也不是很著名，因为这个在当时市场上也不是很成功
but what this format then went on to do is
但这个介质呢，是八分之一英寸宽的磁带，在此之前还没有呢
it developed this tape this eighth of an inch wide tape,
that wasn't out before this format.
This higher quality eighth of an inch wide tape,
这种1/8英寸宽磁带的质量很好，飞利浦盒式磁带上将会使用这种磁带
which then went on to be used in the compact cassette.
So when Philips are looking around to see,
飞利浦当时就在找，这些卡带带里面都有什么呢
well, what can this cassette have in it?
If they were following the Minifon Attaché,
要是他们借鉴Minifon Attaché
they're just using quarter inch wide tape which makes your cartridge a certain size.
用0.25英寸宽的磁带，成品体积会很可观
But you get eighth of an inch wide tape,
要是使用八分之一英寸宽的磁带的话，成品会更小些
you can get a much smaller format,
and effectively that is what has happened here.
基本上，最终就会成为这样
You've gone from 3.75 inches per second with a quarter inch tape
这个是带速每秒3.75英寸，0.25英寸宽的磁带
to 1.875 inches per second with an eighth of an inch tape.
这个是带速每秒1.875英寸，八分之一英寸宽的磁带
And that is the difference in the size of the cassettes.
这就是磁带粗细所带来的区别
So really, it's the tape that's in here.
一句话，磁带的变细是一个很大的技术进步
That is the big development that really made the cassette possible.
也是飞利浦的盒式磁带能够做出来的一个重要方面
Now I just want to mention why this was not a success again
现在，我再谈谈为啥这玩意的售价，让其在市场上不成功
if we just go back to prices.
So in December 1962, they were doing test sales of the system,
所以在1962年12月，他们进行了试售
and it was 450 dollars for a recorder or a player for these cartridges.
录音设备或播放设备需要花费450美元
So 450 dollars, 1962, inflation today, 3900 dollars.
1962年的450美元，算上通胀，现在的3900美元
So the tapes are cheaper, but the machine itself costs a fortune.
磁带很便宜，但机器真的是花费颇多
That's why this wasn't a success.
所以，这是其未能成功的原因
So what Philips did and went on to do is
那么，飞利浦的目标是将这些磁带用在一个简易些的设备上
use this tape format in a much simpler system.
And therefore, a much cheaper system (to) manufacture.
这样的话，新设备的生产成本更低
So again, the cassettes, relatively cheap.
因而，磁带真的很便宜
And if we look back at the price of the first Philips System now,
我们看看第一部飞利浦的盒式磁带播放机的话，是这样的
thing to mention about this.
These were much more popular in Europe,
相比首发地美国来说，磁带在欧洲更加流行
than they were in the US, initially at launch anyway.
So we talking UK price here.
这里我们说的是英国售价
So, the EL3300, which looked much the same as this,
这台EL3300，基本上长成这样
with inflation works out at 538 pounds today.
算上通货膨胀，在今天售卖538英镑
1几尼=1.05英镑
Still a lot of money, but you know, we're not talking insane amounts of money.
虽然价格还是可观，但也并非贵得遥不可及
So yeah, we're comparing UK with US price there,
这里我们比较英美两地的售价，以及两地发行的产品
and products that are from a few years apart from one another.
但两地发行的产品毕竟时间啥的有所不同，所以没法直接比较
So you can't do a direct comparison.
But still, if we just look at the UK price of the compact cassette system,
但是呢，单看英国这里磁带机的售价
the el 3300 at the time it launched,
在EL3300发布的时候，显然，对普通人来说
it was a much more attractive proposition to the average person,
as a tape recorder, than those earlier formats from RCA and 3M.
相比RCA和3M搞的那俩，这是一个价格上更合适的磁带录音机
But it was aimed at a completely different market, really.
不过，这个面向的是一个完全不同的市场
I mean, this is just designed to be
毕竟，这个是被设计用来录制人声的
a simple, easy to use, cassette based audio recorder for voice.
简单易用的磁带录音机
And perhaps you could put a bit of music on it,
兴许录些RickRoll也没问题:-)
SuperBart：或者是一些广播电台播放的歌曲
but it was mono at the time it was launched.
但这玩意首发的时候，只有单声道
Whereas those earlier formats, the 3M and the RCA,
而那些更早的介质，RCA的和3M的
while she could record your own tapes on these,
尽管也能自行在磁带上录音
from the word go, they had pre-recorded music on them in stereo.
他们预灌录的音乐都是双声道的
And they were therefore aiming these as
他们面向的，主要是发烧音乐爱好者
a more market crowd a Hi-Fi audiophile enthusiast.
And that seemed to be the wrong approach
他们看样子走错方向了
because those people have already got all the records or
因为这些人大多已经有录在开盘带上的音乐了，你再让他们去
their reel-to-reel tape recorders, and you then try to encourage them to
get another format with a limited amount of recordings on it.
购买其他的介质，专辑数量也不多
And uh, perhaps a lower quality, well, you just can't do it.
兴许质量还更差，谁会冒这个险呢:-P
I mean they were expensive.
毕竟，这些东西的价格摆在那了
The other people who would be interested
那些有可能入坑HiFi的人，已经拥有那些他们使用过的更好介质了
would be the high-end audio file enthusiast community,
and yeah, they had better formats already that they could have used.
So that was the wrong approach to take Phillips took an approach
他们失败的尝试，促使飞利浦从另一面市场入手
from the other end, really.
They were looking for people who hadn't got any kind of tape recorder or
他们面向的是没有任何磁带机，或是有
had got some basic reel-to-reel machine and
很基本的开盘机，想要找个更方便使用的机器
wanted something that was more convenient to use.
Interestingly though, based on the fact that
有趣的是，尽管已经有了很多的基于磁带的媒介了
there were all those pre-existing formats out there,
the Philips compact cassette, in the end, wasn't that unique of a device.
飞利浦的盒式磁带呢，最终也不是一个那么独特的介质
In fact, there was only one part of this system,
我觉得，整个机器只有一个部分可以申请专利
I believe that, they were able to patent,
or patent something that was unique to the compact cassette.
或是对于磁带来说，可以算是独特到可以申请专利了
And can you think what that particular thing is?
你觉得具体会是哪个部分呢?
I'll just take the lid off to show you.
我把盖子拿掉，给你们演示一下
Right, so this is the unique part of the Philips Compact Cassette.
好的，这就是飞利浦盒式磁带机的独特部分了
That was it, not the button, the movable heads.
就是这个，不是按钮，而是可动的磁头
The way the head comes up into contact with the cassette,
磁头自行移动，和磁带接触的方式
when it's engaged, everything else had static heads.
飞利浦的磁带机是这样的时候，其他的都是固定磁头
So you put the cassette in or the cartridge or whatever,
当你将盒式磁带放进机器，打开开关的时候
you click it into the machine,
but the heads and the pinch roller didn't come up to meet the cassette.
但是磁头和转轮并没有弹出，和磁带接触
They were already in contact with it from the moment it was put in.
从盒式磁带放进的一刻起，他们就和磁带接触上了
So that was the only part of the cassette that was unique.
所以飞利浦的磁带机，也就这点新颖
Interesting side note here, footnote. Some kind of note.
这里我插一句
In 1963, Phillips also launched another tape format.
1963年，飞利浦发行了另一种磁带格式
I don't know if they were trying to hedge their bets.
(不知是不是他们怕盒式磁带不成功，想两边下注)
They weren't sure whether the compact cassette was going to be a success.
But it was this one, this came out in 1963 as well.
就是这个，也是1963年发布
And this is another sort of dictation format.
这个也是给听写机用的
And it comes with these nice little cartridges,
还附带一个挺小，挺耐人的卡带
and the tape gets pulled out of here, and goes into the machine.
磁带从这里扽出来，被拽进机器
And again, it's uh, eighth of an inch wide tape.
当然，这个磁带也是八分之一英寸宽的
So you can see inside here, we've got the tape
我们看看里面，这边的磁带被拽出
that goes in that side take up spool outside,
and the machine automatically threads the tape for you.
机器自动将磁带给你传进那面的盒子里
So again, a more convenient format than strictly open reel.
自然，这个比直接开盘，自己缠磁带方便多了
But I don't quite know what the story was with this.
但我对此设备的开发背后的故事，了解不多
I mean it was obviously in development at the same time as a cassette.
我觉得，这玩意和磁带的开发是同时的啊
And it came out the same year as the compact cassette from Phillips.
然后还和盒式磁带一样，都由飞利浦在同一年发布
Odd that they bring out two kind of similar ideas in the same year.
他们同一年发行两款类似产品，真是奇怪
还有一些尝试
Now of course, it wasn't just Phillips in the early 1960s
当然，上世纪60年代，不止飞利浦想要
who were thinking of producing an easier to use tape-cartridge based system.
开发一种简易易用的磁带-卡带介质
Seems like everyone was having a go at it.
看样子，所有人都想在此方面插一腿
There was loads of different ones in the dictation space particularly.
当时特别在听写机方面，有好多不同的设备
But these are a few that I've shown over the years.
这里我展示一些我这几年展示过的设备
So I've got the Sanyo micro pack 35,
这个是三洋的Micro Pack 35，0.25宽的磁带，卷在两个滚轮上
which is quarter inch tape, stacked on two reels,
that was also sold in the US under the Channel Master name, amongst others.
和其他的一样，这个在美国在Channel Master品牌下销售
There was the "sabermobile".
这个是“Sabermobile”
This is quarter inch tape again, three inch reels, I think.
也是0.25宽的磁带，应该是3寸开盘吧
Then the these two are perhaps the most interesting,
接下来这俩就有些意思了，也是最像飞利浦盒式磁带的
and the most likely Phillips Compact Cassette.
If i can get that one out of there...
等我将其拿出来……
We've got the Grundig DC International,
这个是 Grundig DC International
and then, this Sanyo tape cartridge system.
而这个是三洋的磁带-卡带系统
I'm not too sure if there was a better name than that.
也不知他们有没有当时给这玩意起个更好的名字
But uh, that was one that I featured in a video,
不过呢，关于这个，我在那期视频里展示过
where I got a sears branded tape, which looked very similar to
我是得到了一些Sears牌子的磁带，看上去像磁带，但并不是磁带
the compact cassette, but it wasn't a compact cassette.
The thing with this one is that it was basically a copy.
这玩意基本上就是个复制品啊
Sanyo copied the compact cassette, and came out with that.
三洋抄袭了飞利浦磁带的创意，然后搞出来这个
The Grundig DC International was a little bit more successful,
而 The Grundig DC International 更加成功些
and I've covered the story of the development of this before.
我之前讲过这个的开发历程了
This is kind of an offshoot of the compact cassette.
这算是飞利浦盒式磁带开发时候的一点小插曲吧
Grundig went off on their own, they weren't gonna join up with Phillips.
Grundig 自己开发去了，他们不想和飞利浦一起干
(So) They went and did their own thing.
所以他们自己搞去了
Basically copied the cassette design, but came out with this, the DC International.
基本复制了飞利浦磁带的设计，就搞出来个这个
I'll put a link to the video, where I go into this in better and greater detail.
我做过一期视频，详细介绍这个东西，回来去看看啊
But this was an interesting bargaining chip.
不过这里，我来讲一段有趣的一段议价故事
This was something that was used in the next section I want to talk about,
下一部分，我主要说的就是这件事
which was really the deal that made the compact cassette successful.
就这件事，促使了磁带的成功
And it was when Phillips joined up with Sony.
也就是飞利浦和索尼谈合作的事情
毁誉参半的交易？
Having a bunch of rival, incompatible, and yet, very similar formats on the market
要想让你的产品成功，搞个和竞争对手
is not the way you make a successful product.
十分相似，但互不兼容的竞品是不行的
Phillips wanted the compact cassette to become the
飞利浦想让他们的盒式磁带成为这个领域的单一，全球公认标准
single, worldwide agreed standard.
And for that reason, they went over to Japan,
为此，他们飞到日本，和索尼谈判，想和他们合作
to talk to Sony to get them on board with it.
One of the two people attended that meeting.
有两个人参与了那个会议
By the way, was Lou Ottens, a gentleman we started off
其中有一位，正是我在视频开头说的 Lou Ottens
talking about at the beginning of this video,
but yes, they wanted Sony to sign up to the compact cassette
无论如何，他们想让索尼签下磁带协议
and agree to pay 20 yen for each cassette recorder sold within Japan.
并同意飞利浦在每一台在日本销售的磁带录音机上抽成20日元
Sony disagreed with that idea.
索尼回绝了这个想法
And then Philips said: Okay, all right,
然后飞利浦说：得，每台机器抽成6日元吧
we'll just charge you six yen for each cassette recorder you sell.
Again, Sony pushed back.
索尼又一次回绝了
And the reason they were able to push back
而索尼能够拒绝他们的原因是
is because back in 1963, at that IFA Berlin Show,
在1963年的柏林国际电子消费品展览会上
Grundig, the people behind the DC International, had approached Sony.
生产 DC International 的 Grundig 公司找到了索尼
And asked them to co-develop the DC International Cassette.
想让他们一起合作开发 DC International 磁带
Now Sony had said: No we're not interested.
索尼说：我们不感兴趣
But Grundig went ahead, and also wanted still to get Sony on board with it.
但 Grundig 没有罢休，还是想和索尼合作
Now Sony were more interested in signing up with the Phillips' system,
索尼现在对和飞利浦的磁带签约更感兴趣
but because they were able to say: Well, look, if we don't have to use your cassette.
但是他们也可以说：我们可以不用你们的，用Grundig公司的
We could always go with the DC International.
And they're not going to charge us anything if we go with that one.
我们和他签约的话，他们可不会抽成啊
So Philips had to agree not to charge any licensing fee for
飞利浦要想让索尼接受的话，他们也得同意不向索尼收取授权费
the compact cassette either if they wanted Sony to adopt it.
So they were happier to work with Phillips that they were with Grundig.
这样，索尼和飞利浦合作，较Grundig来得更加愉快
So it all worked out as far as that went, except of course,
目前进展一切顺利，除了一点
Philips weren't getting any licensing fee for
飞利浦并没有对索尼生产的飞利浦盒式磁带录音机抽成
any compact cassette recorders that Sony went on to make.
But part of that deal was non-exclusivity.
但协议中的部分条款是非排他性的
So that effectively meant that anyone who wanted to,
这实际上意味着，任何想做
could make a compact cassette recorder or player, I'll not pay Phillips anything.
飞利浦盒式磁带录音机或播放器的人，他们不必给飞利浦任何东西
And therefore, yes, it did become a worldwide standard.
因此，飞利浦的磁带成了全球标准
It didn't make Phillips rich on licensing fees,
虽然并没有让飞利浦收授权费，赚到很多钱
but it meant that all those different companies
但这意味着那些参与开发过许多不同的卡带播放/录音机的公司
who were involved in the development of
the various different cassette recorders and players,
were then all competing against each other to try and make a better product.
都会尽力生产更好的产品，进而相互竞争
It was like a open source project.
有点像是开源计划了
So you get all these different companies all around the world
这样，全球各地不同的公司都参与进来，生产更好的盒式磁带
involved in making a better cassette.
And that goes all the way back to the people making the tape formulations.
这一切都是从那些研发更好磁带的人开始说起
And that was what created the cassette boom effectively.
而这也是促使了磁带繁荣的开始
Yeah, Phillips started it off started the ball rolling.
没错，飞利浦开了头，之后就是滚雪球那样的繁荣了
But until that day, in 1965 when they met up with Sony,
但直到1965年和索尼的会见
and thrashed out the dealer eventually was finalized in 1966.
以及1966年才结束的和其他公司的谈判之后
It was just a little Phillips product that was sold in Europe.
飞利浦的产品在欧洲的销量并不好
The worldwide phenomenon was created really started in 1966.
全球的盒式磁带流行是从1966年开始的
And by 1967, there were loads of different people making compact cassettes.
到了1967年，好多不同的公司都在生产盒式磁带
In fact, there are a lot of data that I've got here.
实际上，我这里有很多数据
We'll just go through these quickly.
我们快速过一下，因为你们八成已经知道了
Because I'm sure you've got places to be.
But stereo was introduced by Phillips in 1966,
飞利浦在1966年首先发明了双声道盒式磁带
Dolby B came to the cassette in 1968, as did chrome tape as well.
杜比B降噪和铬带是1967年发明的
And the first Hi-Fi deck really was kind of 1970-71 with the Advent 201.
第一个Hifi卡座是1970-71左右出现的Advent 201
So again, really not the Philips product,
再说一遍，不是飞利浦
it was Advent who really brought out the first deck that played cassettes
是Advent首先发布了人们公认的HiFi卡座
that people would really consider as a proper Hi-Fi component.
And then the next big event was courtesy of Sony,
盒式磁带历史的下一个重要时刻是索尼创造的
which I mean, if Sony want on board this one had happened.
当然，如果索尼和飞利浦真合作的话，估计早就发生了
But of course that is, the Walkman, 1979.
话说回来，1979年，磁带随身听诞生
I mean everyone says 1979 really, uh, Japan 1979, perhaps uh, US 1980...
大多数人说的1979年是日本首发，美国得1980年吧……
But you know it's expensive, so it's kind of next few years.
但一开始很贵，所以火起来是接下几年的事情了
But still, cassette sales tripled over the next four years.
不过，盒式磁带的销量在接下了的四年翻了三番
Well, this is a product that have been on the market since 1964-ish.
没错，这可是1964年上市的产品啊
And yeah, in 1979, 80, 81, 82, because sales tripled,
然后，79-82年，销量翻了三倍
well, that's that's really down to this fella.
这件事确实很重要的
And of course, as far as we go into stats here,
当然，再接着看数据呢
the revenue hit the peak for cassettes in the late 1980s.
磁带销量在八十年代末期达至顶峰
And it was the best-selling format,
也是销量最好的音乐格式了
best-selling pre-recorded music format from 1984 to 1992.
从1984年到1992年，都是销量最好的提前灌制好的音乐格式
So that's the best part of a decade.
可以是磁带的黄金十年了
CDs the first time that they sold more than cassettes in the US was 1992.
1992年，在美国，CD的销量头一回超过了磁带
So cassettes had a pretty good run at it as the number one format.
作为销量第一的介质，磁带的成绩十分不错
...0010001001...
And I've just got one final thought about the compact cassette,
关于磁带，我又想到了最后一出
something I'd like to mention, because it often gets overlooked.
我觉得得提一句，因为这件事经常被忽视
It's to do with this in part of a particular area of popular culture.
这件事和某些地区的流行文化相关
And it's not to do with music, it's to do with
这件事和音乐无关，是和电脑，电脑游戏，以及编程相关
computers, and computer games, and programming.
And the early 1980s, in the UK, if you had a Sinclair Spectrum,
在八十年代早期的英国，如果你有如下所列的电脑(名单还能更长)
or Commodore 64, and Abstract CPC 464,
a Dragger 32 and Oricat Moss...
This list could go on, but your primary source of
不过你加载游戏，保存程序的话，你主要的介质就是磁带
loading games and saving programs was to the compact cassette.
And a lot of those kids then went on to create some big programming houses
其中有一些孩子，创建了一些大型软件公司
that then went on to shape the games that we play
然后在更加复杂的平台上，塑造出当代游戏的样子
on far more sophisticated devices.
So as you can see, from all the stuff behind me here,
如你所见，由我后面这么多的史料
the story of the compact cassette is a little bit more complicated than
飞利浦盒式磁带的故事远比那条写着
perhaps, one line in an obituary that states that
“Lou Ottens是飞利浦盒式磁带发明者”的讣告要复杂那么一点吧
Lou Ottens was the inventor of the compact cassette.
Taking nothing away from him at all.
抛开他的其他一些东西
He was the guy. He was the catalyst.
他就是那个伟大的人，他就是磁带出现的催化剂
He was a chap who went into Phillips one day and
有一天，就是他跑进飞利浦办公室，建议团队在这个想法上工作
suggested that they work on this idea.
And that is ultimately what created the compact cassette.
最终，造就了我们所熟知的盒式磁带
But there was a lot of pre-existing cassette or cartridge-based formats
但之前也有很多已经存在的盒式磁带，或卡带类型的格式
that were assimilated into the design of the cassette.
他们的某些设计融入了飞利浦的盒式磁带之中
And then, following the launch of the cassette
然后，随着飞利浦盒式磁带的发布，好多其他格式衰落了
there were other formats fell by the wayside.
And there was a lot of events that were
也有好多东西，说明了为啥只有飞利浦的盒式磁带行，其他的不行
the reasons behind the cassette being the success, where the other formats weren't.
And that's really the story of the cassette.
基本上，磁带的故事就是这样了
So hopefully I've done it a little bit more than
希望我这期视频，不仅仅是在一些常识上扩充了一点东西罢了
just put a bit of meat on the bones for you there.
But that's it for the moment.
不过本期视频就是这样了
As always, thanks for watching.
一如既往，感谢大家收看:-)
感谢以下在Patreon支持我的人;-)
以下是讲故事时间
Homer：我当年听邓丽君的歌，拿着磁带，跑同学家里
用他们家自制的音响播放，音响还得藏在墙里
要被逮到，说你放的是靡靡之音，有你好受的:-P
SuperBart：当时学校发英语磁带，我妈给我买了复读机
然后就是：“北京外国语大学，北京外语音像出版社出版”
当时我还不知道磁带的写保护机制，经常磁带放一会，就是我瞎录的声音
Abraham：我当年有个爱好，拿学校办公室里偷出来的
磁带采访机，录制一些奇奇怪怪的声音，都不知道录了多少了
Hubert：我小学时候使用过两年Boombox，还是外公找人买的松下的
我最后给拆掉了，感到很后悔，那玩意做工是真的很扎实
Peter：真后悔当时没有把我亲戚家的一柜子旧磁带带回来，全给扔了
Robert：外研版小学教材的歌不错，小时候拿一盒朗读带一听就是一下午
Little Dreamer：儿歌大全
Kang Fu Master：外语听力/滑稽
自动字幕整理+翻译：SuperBart 原作者Techmoan发布于2021年3月27日
赞助原作者：https://www.patreon.com/Techmoan
字幕下载：https://github.com/BenderBolg/Subtitles